Joseph Perillo Photograph Collection 1949-1984 (bulk 1975-1984)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Joseph Perillo Photograph Collection 1949-1984 ( bulk 1975-1984)
MS 477
Perillo, Joseph J.
The Joseph Perillo Photograph Collection, 1949-1984 (bulk 1975-1984) contains photographic negatives spanning the career of Joseph Perillo. Prominent Jazz band leaders, singers, athletes and political leaders from the 1940s and 1950s can be found in the collection. Singers, entertainers, and political figures, such as Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, and Pope John Paul II, from the 1970s and 1980s can be found in the collection as well.
0.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Joseph Perillo’s love for photography began when he was in high school. Upon graduating he went on to study photography in New York City. After completing his photography training he went on to enlist in the Air Force. He was an Air Force photographer for several years. While in the Air Force he was part of Public Relations and was assigned as General Davis’s personal photographer. He had the opportunity to photograph many famous people such as Werner Von Braun and Dr. Messerschmitt. His photographs were used in the Air Force Times. After the Air Force, Joseph worked for seven years in Patunent Naval Air Station. During his time at Patunent he worked as a photographer for Grumman Aircraft and the Grumman Newspaper. He also worked in Motion Picture photography and still photography.
The love for Photo Journalism took Joseph to Washington D.C. where he worked for a newspaper. Consequently, he was assigned to the White House where he photographed the administrations of President Gerald Ford and President Jimmy Carter. This gave him the opportunity to photograph many historical milestones such as Pope John Paul visit to the White House and the 1979 Peace treaty signing between Israel and Egypt. Mr. Perillo also photographed for the magazine EUROPE and for the U.S. Park Service Theatre Wolf Trap.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 3 series.
Series I: Early Career,1949-1959
Series II: Political,1975-1979
Series III: Entertainers,1970-1985
Subseries 1: Wolf Trap,1984
Subseries 2: Miscellaneous Events,1970-1985
Scope and Content Note
The collection is composed of negatives of photographs taken by Joseph Perillo from 1949-1985. The negatives span his career as an Air Force and Newspaper Photographer. The collection is divided in to three series. The first series highlights his early career. The negatives in this series consists of famous musicians, singers, and athletes from the 1940-1950s. Some notables are Ella Fitzgerald, Xavier Cugat, Dean Martin, Ray Robinson, Joe DiMaggio, Susan Vaughan, Nat King Cole and Gene Krupa. Series two, his political images, consist of negatives that span the administrations of Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter as well as other political figures including Edward Kennedy and Werner Von Braun. Series Three, Entertainers, is composed of two subseries. Subseries 1, contains negatives from performances and events that were held at Wolf Trap in 1984. Included in these negatives are performances by Placido Domingo, Ella Fitzgerald, and Liza Minnelli. Subseries 2, includes negatives of famous artists in different events and locations. Ansel Adams, Duke Ellington and Frank Sinatra can be found within this subseries.
Access Terms
Perillo, Joseph J.
Carter, Jimmy, 1924-
Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006
Photojournalism—20th century
John Paul -- II, -- Pope, -- 1920-2005.
Jazz Musicians—1940-1950
Big Bands—United States
Wolf Trap National Park for the Performing Arts (Va.)
Women entertainers
Entertainers
Negative Prints
Container List
- Series I: Early Career, 1949-1959
  This series is arranged alphabetically. It contains negatives of various musicians, singers, athletes, and personalities of the era.
  - Count Basie, 1953> (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tex Beneke,1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Milton Berle,1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Connie Boswell,1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Candy” Candido,1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dick Cantino,1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nat “King” Cole,1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Xavier Cugat,1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vic Damone,1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Joe Dimaggio,1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Billy Eckstine,1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ella Fitzgerald,1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Norman Granz,1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Illinois Jacquet,1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gene Krupa,1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Guy Lambrado,1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Frankie Lane,1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ralph Marteri,1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dean Martin,1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chico Marx,1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ray Mckinley,1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - James Melton,1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Noro Morales,1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Al Morgan,1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Patti Page,1950 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Louis Prima,1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Jackie Robinson,1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ray Robinson,1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Hazel Scott,1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Zachary Scott,1953 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cardinal Spellman,1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Sarah Vaughan,1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Billy Ward and Group,1950 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Series II: Political,1975-1979
  This series is arranged alphabetically. It contains negatives of President Carter, President Ford and other politicians. It also contains negatives of several significant events in their administrations.
  - Zbigniew Brezezinski,undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Father’s Day Jazz Celebration,June 1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Betty Ford,1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - President Ford and Christmas Celebrations,1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Governor Carter on campaign trail,1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - President Carter and President Ceausescu of Romania,undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - President Carter and Japanese Prime Minister Takeo Fukuda,undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - President Carter and President Portillo of Mexico,undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - President Carter and Jody Powell in Oval Office,undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Senator Edward Kennedy,1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Peace Treaty Signing by Egypt and Israel,1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Pope John Paul II visit to the White House,1979 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Werner Von Braun Reception Party,undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - John Warner for Senator Campaign,1978 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - John Warner, Elizabeth Taylor and John Dalton,undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series III: Entertainers
  This series contains two subseries. The first contains negatives of performances and events at Wolf Trap. The second contains negatives of entertainers and artist at several different events. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 1: Wolf trap,1984
    - Judy Collins,undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - John Davidson “Oklahoma”,1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Johnny Desmond and Helen O’Connel,1984 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Johnny Desmond, Helen O’ Connel, Peter Marshall and Tex Beneke,1984 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Placido Domingo,1984 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Ella Fitzgerald and Oscar Peterson,1984 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Gala,1984 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Liza Minnelli and Sammy Davis Jr.,undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Renata Scott and John Alexandra,1984 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Temptations and the Four Tops,undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Frankie Valli and the Four Seasons,1984 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Subseries 2: Miscellaneous Events,1970-1980
    - Ansel Adams,1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Vikki Carr,1973 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Cyd Charisse,1981 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Phil Donahue,undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Duke Ellington,undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Frank Sinatra,undated (Box 1, Folder 65)